MICHAEL JOHN

SKILLS

Back End

Python · Django · Flask

Front End

React · Vue.js · Next.js · Angualr · Jinja

Database

MySQL · PostgreSQL · MongoDB

Option

AWS Lambda · RESTful API

INDUSTRY EXPERTISE

Important expertise in the job description

LANGUAGES

English E

••••

Japanese Intermediate

intermediate

PROJECTS

Motor Vehicle Department

07/2017 - 01/2019

Location

Short summary of your work

 VERIFI (Vehicle Electronic Reassignment andIntegrated Facility Inventory) " is a highly secure, Web-based system that will replace the current paperbased processes in the motor vehicle department

https://www.verifiny.com/

Full Stack Developer

RESUME PROFILE

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 6+ years experience in web applications and databases. Spearheaded successful transition from MERN stack to Django + Vue, Flask + Jinja2 which cut latency by 40% and increased effectiveness of database administrators by 20%. Seeking to further improve HTML5 and CSS3 skills as the future full stack developer at Atmospheric Solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Developer

11/2018 - 06/2021

VentureDive

Toronto. CA

VentureDive Pvt. Ltd. is a technology solutions company based in Karachi, Pakistan founded in 2012.

- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Liaised with back end developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO as needed.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Junior Web Developer

11/2014 - 10/2018

SIGNA

Toronto. CA

Software development company in Chennai, India

- · Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Used various ideas from distributed computing, large-scale design, real-time data processing, data storage, ML, and Al to solve challenging dataset problems.
- · Managed, optimized, and updated PHP databases as necessary.
- Developed app integration with REST / SOAP and other APIs for Google Maps, social media logins, payment processors, and other services

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science

04/2010 - 03/2014

Toronto University Mississauga

Toronto. CA